It's the breaking news of the week.
Google has just released Gemini 3. And
so right now, I want to show you the
benchmarks. We're going to build a
landing page together in the new
anti-gravity. And that's going to be all
it takes to show you that Gemini 3 is
the most powerful LLM that has ever been
created. Just kidding. It is not that
simple. And that's actually what I want
to cover with you today. Because
whenever these new LLMs are released,
they get a ton of hype and they're
always crushing it on the benchmarks.
But then often when you try the LLM
yourself for something like AI coding,
you see an entirely different picture.
Now, Gemini 3 is a genuinely impressive
model. Don't get me wrong, we'll cover
that as well. You can't deny that even
if you take these benchmarks with a big
grain of salt. The jumps that we have
here are insane. But the problem that I
want to focus on with you is that these
benchmarks, they kind of seem like
marketing material. And we know that
these large language models are getting
trained more and more to solve these
kinds of tests and tasks. And so that
leaves us with the question of like how
do we actually know if an LLM is really
the next big thing? And it kind of just
comes down to you have to try it
yourself, wait for millions of other
people to try it, and then establish a
kind of common opinion. Like we know
that Claude Sonnet 4.5 is generally
considered the best LLM for coding, at
least before Gemini 3. But that kind of
common opinion, you can't even trust
that and it's far from an immediate
eval. So, we're stuck looking at these
benchmarks. Now, there is a solution to
this that I've seen surface recently. I
want to cover that with you as well. So,
this video is going to be really just no
fluff. We got something big in the
industry right now. Let's talk about the
problems. Let's talk about the
solutions. All right. When we think
about evals for LLMs, it helps to focus
on a specific domain. So, I'm going to
focus on AI coding, especially because
of anti-gravity, Google's new AI IDE
that integrates with Gemini 3. Very
cool. We'll talk about that in a little
bit. But here's our problem. On the left
hand side, we have our benchmarks. This
really nice curve here showing the
apparent explosion in capabilities for
our LLMs over the last months and years.
But then on the right hand side,
developer productivity is just a flat
line. So, as these LMS have gotten more
and more powerful, it hasn't actually
translated to the real world, at least
with this study here, examining top
contributors to big open source
projects, which in my mind is pretty
legit. And my experience, I can kind of
relate to this. Obviously, the results
that I've been getting with AI coding
assistance has completely exploded over
the last year. I talk about that all the
time in my agenda coding course on my
YouTube channel, but it might and just
might be more thanks to my tools and AI
coding system than it is the underlying
large language model. And so just as a
little bit of a throwback, I was using
Windsurf way back in the day. Well, I
say way back in the day, but this is
like the start of this year and late
last year. And within Windsurf um at
this time I was using Claude Sonnet 3.5
which is like four generations old at
this point. So as far as LLMs go it's
really really old. And so now obviously
I am using Claude code with Sonnet 4.5
and the results I'm getting are better
like I said. But if I were to plug in
Sonnet 3.5 into my current tooling and
AI system I wonder how close the results
actually would be. I mean, even back
then, Sonnet 3.5 was crushing it for me,
and I was developing at lightning speed
compared to using no AI coding
assistance at all. And so, it's just
interesting to think like how much of it
is more just like our tools and systems
on top of LMS making them seem more
powerful when the underlying reasoning
really is a flat line. Now, I'm curious
what you think. Like, let me know in the
comments what you think on this because
honestly, it's hard for me to evaluate
this kind of thing myself. I'd have to
go all the way back to Sonnet 3.5 and
test it on a ton of more complex use
cases I've been working on recently. I
mean, that's the problem we have where
we rely on benchmarks because the
alternative is just something that's
really complex. Okay, so our core
problem here, large language models are
getting more powerful, but to what
extent? It might be the tools we're
adding on top of the LLMs that are
making more of the difference. And here
in Google's new anti-gravity, I have a
really good example of this. And so this
is their new AI IDE, obviously using
Gemini 3 by default. And Gemini 3 seems
to be so good at designs and building
frontends. That's what I've been testing
it with over the weekend here. And it
seems like it's better than something
like Claude Sonnet 4.5. But is it really
the case or is it some tools that we
have built into anti-gravity? One of the
things that we have in anti-gravity that
is very cool is a Google Chrome
integration. And so what we're able to
do within anti-gravity is ask the AI
coding assistant to verify websites.
It'll open up its own browser that it
can navigate autonomously. So it can
visit websites after it starts them up
and it can validate things visually.
It's very very powerful. So for this
simple demonstration here, I just asked
it to analyze my codebase so it knows
how to start up the front end, scroll
through it, and then recommend
suggestions for making the website look
better. So, taking advantage of the
vision capabilities of Gemini 3 as well.
And it worked extremely well. And not
only can you have it visit sites
autonomously, but you can also go
through and you can watch its work. And
so I can go in here, I can take a look
at the screenshot that I captured on my
website. I can view the playback. So I
can watch it scroll through things and
click on buttons and go between pages
and things like that. It is so so cool.
And so one thing that I did run into
with Gemini 3 in anti-gravity is it kept
getting an overload error. So I just
have to keep asking it to continue. So
you might encounter this yourself if you
use anti-gravity. But the point that I'm
trying to show here is that it has this
new capability added on top of the LLM
that makes it a lot better at working
with frontends and designs. And I was
super impressed with the results that I
got here. Okay, so I'll show you this
live right now. I'll ask it to visit
this website that I already have
running. I could have also asked it to
spin up even the website itself. But
yeah, this is just so cool. We can watch
it navigate the site autonomously, which
this isn't a brand new thing. You can do
this with the Playright or Stage Hand
MCP servers, for example. I've even
shown that on my channel before, but
this seems to really be optimized for
anti-gravity specifically. And having
this as a built-in integration is
really, really cool. And just the way
that, for example, it waits 5 seconds
before it captures the screenshot to
make sure the page is rendered, like
that kind of thing. It's sort of like
baked into the system prompt for this
Google Chrome integration. Really,
really cool. And so you can see it like
scroll through the site there. If I go
back into the IDE, I can view the
screenshot that it took and the playback
like I showed earlier. But this is all
happening live now. Very, very powerful.
And in general, anti-gravity is a
fantastic AI IDE. They also have their
agent manager mode. So it takes the code
out of the picture in the IDE. So we're
just working with the conversations with
our coding assistants. We can kick off
tasks in parallel between our different
repositories. We can also view the code
that it changed. We can add comments
line by line, so more of a traditional
code review, which is also really neat.
So yeah, let me know in the comments if
you want me to cover anti-gravity in
another video. I think this is an AI IDE
that is worth paying attention to. So
going back to the benchmarks here, it is
clear from my testing that Gemini 3 is a
very powerful LLM. And even though I do
take these benchmarks with a grain of
salt, this test in particular, the
results that Gemini 3 got here is insane
because ARC AGI 2, it is a lot more than
just pattern recognition. It's giving
tasks to the LLM that requires a lot of
abstract reasoning. And so, yeah, Gemini
3 is legit. But like I said, the problem
that I have here is when I'm testing it
myself, there's a lot of tools and
systems built on top. And so even after
this weekend, I really don't feel like I
have a super solidified idea in my mind
of how powerful Gemini 3 actually is.
And so that's where we get into the
solution that I want to introduce here.
The higher level idea and then one in
particular with Kleinbench. Think about
this with me for a second. If only there
was a massive set of publicly available
repositories where you could see how
they change over time as real engineers
are working on real tasks with AI coding
assistants. Oh wait, that's exactly what
we have with open source repos,
especially with something like GitHub.
And that is what Klein is going to be
leveraging with Kleinbench. And now I'm
not affiliated with him at all, but I
really do think that they're on the
frontier now of LLM evals, especially as
it relates to agentic coding. And the
problem they go over at the start of
this article is exactly what I've been
talking about today. Our benchmarks just
don't resemble how we are actually using
large language models in the wild. And
so for coding specifically, it's all
just a bunch of leak code style puzzles
like reversing a linked list for
example. And I know this is AI coding
specifically, but you can extrapolate
this like I've been saying to any
benchmark. And so what client bench is
doing for us, there's three primary
purposes. First is reliable evaluation.
So instead of relying on these synthetic
benchmarks, we are now working on real
engineering tasks. And so when you opt
in to use client for this, it's privacy
first. You have to opt in. Obviously, it
will track your prompts and how you're
working on these real engineering tasks
with client on your open source
repositories so that we have real
engineering tasks for our eval. And then
also by standardizing and publishing
these environments like we obviously
have to work in controlled environments
to make these eval reliable. It's also a
way for us to document system gaps and
so we can learn how to use AI coding
assistance better as we are creating
these eval. And then also this is all
going to be training data for research
and fine-tuning down the line. And I
know that training data is always a
scary thing for privacy but they have
this at the top of their mind. So they
talk about that as well. This is
something that you have to opt into and
is only available for open-source
repositories. And client bench has
designed things very very intelligently.
There's just three pieces of information
that we need for any real engineering
task. We need the starting snapshot of
the repository, their prompt, and then
also the end state or the code that was
actually committed to the open- source
repository. Now, I hope that starting
prompt can also be extended to many
different prompts if you have a whole
system you run before you make your
commit. But yeah, the point here is that
it's really simple. We just need the
starting state, the process, and the
ending state. That's all we need for our
eval. Now, it's kind of simple just
looking at it here, but really under the
hood, there's a lot of challenges that
client is going to have to address
because like we've been talking about,
different engineers are going to be
using different tools and systems as
they work with their AI coding
assistance. And so, we have to account
for that because maybe one engineer gets
a lot better results with Gemini 3 just
because they have more of a process than
someone that's using Cloud Sonnet 4.5.
But as long as that is documented in the
process here and they have some kind of
standard for these agentic engineering
environments like they talked about up
here. As long as we have that standard
then this is going to be so powerful
giving us real world data understanding
the LLM that we should use for our own
projects. And that's the whole point of
this video is to show you that like this
is the direction we're heading to make
it so that you know better the tools and
LLM to use for the things that you want
to create. And one thing I want to be
really clear on here is that clientbench
might not end up being the standard for
AI coding eval. The point is not the
individual company or tool, just that we
have to move to real tasks for
evaluating our LLMs for things like AI
coding. And that's everything that I've
got for you today. One thing I want to
plug really quickly is that I have a
super exciting live stream happening
November 29th at 9:00 a.m. Central time.
I'm going to be giving away my remote
agentic coding system that I've been
working really hard on recently, but I'm
only giving it away during the live
stream itself. So, come be a part of it.
It is going to be an absolute blast. And
so, with that, if you appreciate this
video and you're looking forward to more
things on AI coding, I'd really
appreciate a like and a subscribe. And
with that, I will see you on the live
stream on November 29th.